# KYLE D. KLEVEN \_ SR QUALITY ANALYST

kyle.kleven@outlook.com www.linkedin.com/in/kdkleven https://github.com/kdkleven

#### SUMMARY

Highly motivated QA professional with over 15 years of experience testing software applications. Driver of quality testing practices and standards across Realogy (ABT) products. Championed all phases of the software test life cycle on over video game 50 projects, including every major Call of Duty title from 2014 to 2019. Earned the nickname "The Machine" as a QA Analyst because of my dedication towards producing high quality products and determination to overcome challenges.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**Senior QA Analyst** | Agent Broker Technology/Realogy, Edina, MN | Jul 2019 – Present Develop test plans and test cases used for both manual and automated testing. Conduct manual and automated testing for functionality, integration, installation, and usability. Define and track quality assurance metrics. Manage project workflow with respect to QA items. Coordinate and prioritize testing of applications modifications, enhancements, and fixes. Collaborate with multiple developers across teams and projects. Contracted through Horizontal Integration.

**QA Manager** | Activision Publishing Inc., Eden Prairie, MN | Sep 2009 – Jan 2019 Spearheaded functionality testing efforts during development of the most played video game software products on the market. Led test teams through all aspects of the STLC. Completed 29 projects with a duration of 6 to 36 months per project. Notable projects include: Rapala Pro Bass Fishing, NASCAR The Game, Prototype 2, Call of Duty: Black Ops 3, Deadpool, Call of Duty: WWII, Crash Bandicoot N. Sane Trilogy, Call of Duty: Black Ops 4, Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice, Call of Duty Companion App, and Call of Duty Mobile.

- 13 years of experience conducting integration, system, and acceptance testing across multiple platforms simultaneously (e.g., game console, mobile device, web browser, and peripherals).
- 12 years of experience gathering user requirements, compiling the test strategy, creating test plans, developing test cases, executing test cases, conducting regression testing, and closing projects.
- 12 years of experience using DevTrack and Jira testing for and investigating bugs, logging detailed defect reports, manage database workflow, and assess project health through metrics and trends analysis.
- 3 years of leading and executing functionality, compliance, and compatibility testing of Activision's family of websites, single-sign-on system, user forums, as well as multiple applications developed for mobile/tablet, IoT and web browser integration.
- Coordinated testing efforts across multiple projects simultaneously, resolved problems daily, negotiated solutions with internal and external business partners, and prioritize resources to ensure projects were operating with optimal efficiency and efficacy.
- Identified a need for improved tester training, then redesigned a 5-day lecture into a 3-day interactive
  "test and learn" program, enabling testers to onboard their projects two days faster, and with clearer
  expectations.
- Designed, developed and launched a centralized QA knowledgebase to improve cross-functional understanding for all teams by making access to useful information, key documents, and training materials easier and consistent.
- Successfully orchestrated numerous large-scale multiplayer tests involving 100+ active participants (located in both on-site and remote environments) to conduct server load, performance, and stability testing.
- Guided the implementation of automation testing and productivity tools developed to improve daily routines and facilitate monotonous testing.
- Intermediate experience in SQL and Access databases.
- Intermediate experience in Linux OS and Linux command line (coursework in progress).
- Beginner level knowledge of Git, Ruby, Selenium WebDriver, TFS, Cucumber, and Visual Studio.

**QA Analyst/Sr. QA Analyst** | Activision Publishing Inc., Eden Prairie, MN | Jun 2006 – Sep 2009 Created formalized test plans and test case frameworks for all assigned projects throughout integration, system, and user acceptance testing cycles. Exercised reasonable judgment in application and interpretation of software standards and design requirements. Completed 9 projects with a duration of 6 to 9 months per project. Notable projects: The History Channel: Civil War, Soldier of Fortune: Payback, Ferrari Challenge: Trofeo Pirelli, and Bakugan: Battle Brawlers.

- Gathered user requirements, authored test plans, developed test cases, setup the test environment, executed functionality test cases while leading a team of testers, reported and reviewed thousands of defects, conduct regression testing, tracked metrics and trends, and close projects.
- Provided guidance to Junior QA Analysts and Testers to ensure quality standards were maintained through test execution.
- Developed deep knowledge of quality assurance methods and practices.

**QA Analyst** | Activision Value Publishing Inc., Eden Prairie, MN | Jul 2005 – Jun 2006 Quickly excelled at manual testing, specifically around exploratory testing and user experience. Became adept at functionality testing, defect reporting, test case execution, exploratory testing, and regression sweeps. Completed 7 projects with a duration of 4 to 6 months per project. Notable projects: World Series of Poker, Cabela's Alaskan Adventures, and Greg Hastings Tournament Paintball MAX'd.

### **EDUCATION**

**Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp |** University of Minnesota | Dec 2020 – Present Learned Technologies: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Node, Express server, Server-side APIs, Third Party APIs, Bootstrap, Mongo DB, SQL Server, Sequelize, Mongoose, MVC architecture, React, IndexedDB.

Online Coursework | Udemy | Jan 2019 - Present

Relevant Courses: Postgres SQL, Python, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Java, Selenium, Team Foundation Server, Cucumber, Linux command line, REST APIs, Maven, JUnit, and Git.

**A.A.S. in Software Engineering |** Minnesota School of Business | Sep 2002 - Dec 2004 Relevant Courses: C, C++, Java, VB, .NET, HTML, and SQL Server.

#### **NOTABLE PROJECTS**

Daily Recreational | https://kdkleven.github.io/dailyRecreational/

Daily Recreational provides information on National Parks and Activities in your desired area to inspire you to get out of the house and rekindle your love for outdoor activities. The application is built with Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node, and Express, paired with the National Parks Service API to provide NPS data.

Cup of Sugar | https://cup-of-sugar-application.herokuapp.com/

Cup of Sugar is simply a platform for good neighbors to be good neighbors. Users can easily find local and national resources, browse posts about what resources or services are available or needed in their community, and connect with one another to help fulfill those needs. Users can create posts of their own as well where they can offer up free food or clothing, or to ask for help with something in their home. The application is built with Javascript, HTML, CSS, Boostrap, Handlebars, Express, Node.

Tech Blog | https://kk-tech-blog.herokuapp.com/

Tech Blog designed for users to post their tech findings, ideas, and opinions, and comment on each other's posts. The application was built using Node, Express, Bootstrap, MongoDB, and Mongoose.

### REFERENCES

**Jason Lembcke** from Activision Publishing Inc. | <u>jason.lembcke@activision.com</u> | (612) 242-2402 Direct supervisor for 13 years.

**Justin Westplate** from Activision Publishing Inc. | <u>justinwestplate@gmail.com</u> | (612) 670-7871 Peer within the same group for 10 years.

**Matt McCullough** from Activision Publishing Inc. | <u>mattrmcc@gmail.com</u> | (612) 532-2755 Peer within the same company for 8 years.